ATHLETICS - BRUSSELS GRAND PRIX RESULTS .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-23
Leading results in the <LOCATION>Brussels</LOCATION>
Grand Prix athletics meeting on Friday :
Women's discus
1. Ilke Wyludda ( <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> ) 66.60 metres
2. Ellina Zvereva ( <LOCATION>Belarus</LOCATION> ) 65.66
3. Franka Dietzsch ( <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> ) 61.74
4. Natalya Sadova ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 61.64
5. Mette Bergmann ( Norway ) 61.44
6. Nicoleta Grasu ( Romania ) 61.36
7. Olga Chernyavskaya ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 60.46
8. Irina Yatchenko ( <LOCATION>Belarus</LOCATION> ) 58.92
Women's 100 metres hurdles
1. Ludmila Engquist ( Sweden ) 12.60 seconds
2. Michelle Freeman ( <LOCATION>Jamaica</LOCATION> ) 12.77
3. Aliuska Lopez ( Cuba ) 12.85
4. Dionne Rose ( <LOCATION>Jamaica</LOCATION> ) 12.88
5. Brigita Bukovec ( <LOCATION>Slovakia</LOCATION> ) 12.95
6. Yulia Graudin ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 12.96
7. <PERSON>Julie Baumann</PERSON> ( <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION> ) 13.36
8. <PERSON>Patricia Girard-Leno</PERSON> ( <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> ) 13.36
9. Dawn Bowles ( U.S. ) 13.53
Men's 110 metres hurdles
1. Allen Johnson ( U.S. ) 12.92 seconds
2. <PERSON>Colin Jackson</PERSON> ( Britain ) 13.24
3. Emilio Valle ( Cuba ) 13.33
4. Sven Pieters ( <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> ) 13.37
5. Steve Brown ( U.S. ) 13.38
6. Frank Asselman ( <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> ) 13.64
7. Hubert Grossard ( <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> ) 13.65
8. Jonathan N'Senga ( <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> ) 13.66
9. Johan Lisabeth ( <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> ) 13.75
Women's 5,000 metres
1. Roberta Brunet ( <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> ) 14 minutes 48.96 seconds
2. Fernanda Ribeiro ( <LOCATION>Portugal</LOCATION> ) 14:49.81
3. Sally Barsosio ( Kenya ) 14:58.29
4. Paula Radcliffe ( Britain ) 14:59.70
5. Julia Vaquero ( <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> ) 15:04.94
6. Catherine McKiernan ( Ireland ) 15:07.57
7. Annette Peters ( U.S. ) 15:07.85
8. Pauline Konga ( Kenya ) 15:11.40
Men's 100 metres
1. Dennis Mitchell ( U.S. ) 10.03 seconds
2. Donovan Bailey ( <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> ) 10.09
3. Carl Lewis ( U.S. ) 10.10
4. <PERSON>Ato Boldon ( Trinidad</PERSON> ) 10.12
5. Linford Christie ( Britain ) 10.14
6. Davidson Ezinwa ( <LOCATION>Nigeria</LOCATION> ) 10.15
7. Jon Drummond ( U.S. ) 10.16
8. Bruny Surin ( <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> ) 10.30
Men's 400 metres hurdles
1. Derrick Adkins ( U.S. ) 47.93 seconds
2. Samuel Matete ( <LOCATION>Zambia</LOCATION> ) 47.99
3. Rohan Robinson ( <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> ) 48.86
4. Torrance Zellner ( U.S. ) 49.06
5. <PERSON>Jean-Paul Bruwier</PERSON> ( Belgium ) 49.24
6. Dusan Kovacs ( Hungary ) 49.31
7. Calvin Davis ( U.S. ) 49.49
8. Laurent Ottoz ( <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> ) 49.61
9. Marc Dollendorf ( Belgium ) 50.36
Women's 100 metres
1. Gail Devers ( U.S. ) 10.84 seconds
2. Gwen Torrence ( U.S. ) 11.00
3. Merlene Ottey ( <LOCATION>Jamaica</LOCATION> ) 11.04
4. Mary Onyali ( <LOCATION>Nigeria</LOCATION> ) 11.09
5. Chryste Gaines ( U.S. ) 11.18
6. Zhanna Pintusevich ( Ukraine ) 11.27
7. Irina Privalova ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 11.28
8. Natalia Voronova ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 11.28
9. Juliet Cuthbert ( <LOCATION>Jamaica</LOCATION> ) 11.31
Women's 1,500 metres
1. Regina Jacobs ( U.S. ) 4 minutes 01.77 seconds
2. Patricia Djate ( <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> ) 4:02.26
3. Carla Sacramento ( <LOCATION>Portugal</LOCATION> ) 4:02.67
4. Yekaterina Podkopayeva ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 4:04.78
5. Margret Crowley ( <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> ) 4:05.00
6. Leah Pells ( <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> ) 4:05.64
7. Sarah Thorsett ( U.S. ) 4:06.80
8. Sinead Delahunty ( Ireland ) 4:07.27
3,000 metres steeplechase
1. Joseph Keter ( Kenya ) 8 minutes 10.02 seconds
2. <PERSON>Patrick Sang ( Kenya</PERSON> ) 8:12.04
3. Moses Kiptanui ( Kenya ) 8:12.65
4. Gideon Chirchir ( Kenya ) 8:15.69
5. Richard Kosgei ( Kenya ) 8:16.80
6. Larbi El Khattabi ( <LOCATION>Morocco</LOCATION> ) 8:17.29
7. Eliud Barngetuny ( Kenya ) 8:17.66
8. Bernard Barmasai ( Kenya ) 8:17.94
Men's 400 metres
1. Michael Johnson ( U.S. ) 44.29 seconds
2. Derek Mills ( U.S. ) 44.78
3. Anthuan Maybank ( U.S. ) 44.92
4. <PERSON>Davis Kamoga ( Uganda</PERSON> ) 44.96
5. Jamie Baulch ( Britain ) 45.08
6. Sunday Bada ( <LOCATION>Nigeria</LOCATION> ) 45.21
7. Samson Kitur ( Kenya ) 45.34
8. Mark Richardson ( Britain ) 45.67
9. Jason Rouser ( U.S. ) 46.11
Men's 200 metres
1. Frankie Fredericks ( Namibia ) 19.92 seconds
2. <PERSON>Ato Boldon ( Trinidad</PERSON> ) 19.99
3. Jeff Williams ( U.S. ) 20.21
4. Jon Drummond ( U.S. ) 20.42
5. Patrick Stevens ( Belgium ) 20.42
6. Michael Marsh ( U.S. ) 20.43
7. Ivan Garcia ( Cuba ) 20.45
8. Eric Wymeersch ( Belgium ) 20.84
9. Lamont Smith ( U.S. ) 21.08
Women's 1,000 metres
1. Svetlana Masterkova ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 2 minutes 28.98 seconds
( world record )
2. Maria Mutola ( Mozambique ) 2:29.66
3. Malgorzata Rydz ( Poland ) 2:39.00
4. Anja Smolders ( Belgium ) 2:43.06
5. Veerle De Jaeghere ( Belgium ) 2:43.18
6. Eleonora Berlanda ( <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> ) 2:43.44
7. Anneke Matthijs ( Belgium ) 2:43.82
8. Jacqueline Martin ( Spain ) 2:44.22
Women's 200 metres
1. Mary Onyali ( <LOCATION>Nigeria</LOCATION> ) 22.42 seconds
2. Inger Miller ( U.S. ) 22.66
3. Irina Privalova ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 22.68
4. Natalia Voronova ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 22.73
5. Marina Trandenkova ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 22.84
6. Chandra Sturrup ( Bahamas ) 22.85
7. Zundra Feagin ( U.S. ) 23.18
8. Galina Malchugina ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 23.25
Women's 400 metres
1. Cathy Freeman ( <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> ) 49.48 seconds
2. Marie-Jose Perec ( <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> ) 49.72
3. Falilat Ogunkoya ( <LOCATION>Nigeria</LOCATION> ) 49.97
4. <PERSON>Pauline Davis</PERSON> ( Bahamas ) 50.14
5. Fatima Yussuf ( <LOCATION>Nigeria</LOCATION> ) 50.14
6. Maicel Malone ( U.S. ) 50.51
7. Hana Benesova ( Czech Republic ) 51.71
8. Ann Mercken ( Belgium ) 53.55
Men's 3,000 metres
1. Daniel Komen ( Kenya ) 7 minutes 25.87 seconds
2. Khalid Boulami ( <LOCATION>Morocco</LOCATION> ) 7:31.65
3. Bob Kennedy ( U.S. ) 7:31.69
4. El Hassane Lahssini ( <LOCATION>Morocco</LOCATION> ) 7:32.44
5. Thomas Nyariki ( Kenya ) 7:35.56
6. Noureddine Morceli ( <LOCATION>Algeria</LOCATION> ) 7:36.81
7. Fita Bayesa ( Ethiopia ) 7:38.09
8. <PERSON>Martin Keino ( Kenya</PERSON> ) 7:38.88
Men's discus
1. Lars Riedel ( <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> ) 66.74 metres
2. Anthony Washington ( U.S. ) 66.72
3. Vladimir Dubrovshchik ( <LOCATION>Belarus</LOCATION> ) 64.02
4. Virgilius Alekna ( Lithuania ) 63.62
5. Juergen Schult ( <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> ) 63.48
6. Vassiliy Kaptyukh ( <LOCATION>Belarus</LOCATION> ) 61.80
7. Vaclavas Kidikas ( Lithuania ) 60.92
8. <PERSON>Michael Mollenbeck</PERSON> ( <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> ) 59.24
Men's triple jump
1. <PERSON>Jonathan Edwards</PERSON> ( Britain ) 17.50 metres
2. Yoelvis Quesada ( Cuba ) 17.29
3. Brian Wellman ( <LOCATION>Bermuda</LOCATION> ) 17.05
4. Kenny Harrison ( U.S. ) 16.97
5. Gennadi Markov ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 16.66
6. Francis Agyepong ( Britain ) 16.63
7. Rogel Nachum ( Israel ) 16.36
8. Sigurd Njerve ( Norway ) 16.35
Men's 1,500 metres
1. Hicham El Guerrouj ( <LOCATION>Morocco</LOCATION> ) three minutes 29.05 seconds
2. Isaac Viciosa ( <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> ) 3:33.00
3. William Tanui ( Kenya ) 3:33.36
4. Elijah Maru ( Kenya ) 3:33.64
5. Marcus O'Sullivan ( Ireland ) 3:33.77
6. John Mayock ( Britain ) 3:33.94
7. Laban Rotich ( Kenya ) 3:34.12
8. Christophe Impens ( Belgium ) 3:34.13
Women's high jump
1. Stefka Kostadinova ( <LOCATION>Bulgaria</LOCATION> ) 2.03 metres
2. Inga Babakova ( Ukraine ) 2.03
3. Alina Astafei ( <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> ) 1.97
4. Tatyana Motkova ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 1.94
5. Svetlana Zalevskaya ( <LOCATION>Kazakhstan</LOCATION> ) 1.91
6. Yelena Gulyayeva ( <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> ) 1.88
7. Hanna Haugland ( Norway ) 1.88
8 equal .
Olga Boshova ( <LOCATION>Moldova</LOCATION> ) 1.85
8 equal .
Nele Zilinskiene ( Lithuania ) 1.85
Men's 10,000 metres
1. Salah Hissou ( <LOCATION>Morocco</LOCATION> ) 26 minutes 38.08 seconds ( world
record )
2. Paul Tergat ( Kenya ) 26:54.41
3. <PERSON>Paul Koech ( Kenya</PERSON> ) 26:56.78
4. <PERSON>William Kiptum ( Kenya</PERSON> ) 27:18.84
5. Aloys Nizigama ( Burundi ) 27:25.13
6. Mathias Ntawulikura ( Rwanda ) 27:25.48
7. Abel Anton ( <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> ) 28:18.44
8. Kamiel Maase ( Netherlands ) 28.29.42
9. Worku Bekila ( Ethiopia ) 28.42.23
10. Robert Stefko ( <LOCATION>Slovakia</LOCATION> ) 28:42.26

